

MIGUEL PINTO

WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- migueljcpinto@gmail.com
- 81737 Munich
- +49 (0) 172 6740488
- in linkedin.com/in/migueljcpinto
- github.com/migueljcpinto



TECH SKILLS

- HTML,
- CSS, TailwindCSS,
- JavaScript, Typescript,
- React.js,
- NoSQL MongoDB
- SQL MySQL
- Node.js
- · GitHub, Git
- Figma (Basics)
- Next.js
- Agile Methoden Scrum

LANGUAGES

- Portuguese Native
- · German Working language
- English Good knowledge
- Spanish Good knowledge

HOBBIES

Running, swimming, CrossFit, cinema and travelling

PERSONAL PROFILE

Passionate about healthcare and digital technology, I have advanced my career as a nurse while cultivating my interest in web development. With my skills as an analytical, task-oriented problem solver and my experience collaborating in multidisciplinary teams as an intensive care nurse, I can make a valuable contribution. I am excited about new opportunities and look forward to collectively making positive impacts.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bootcamp Web Development

2023 | Intensive Coding-Bootcamp in Part-time - 540 Hours Neuefische School, Remote | Final project - <u>Team Up</u>

- Experienced in the use of modern technologies such as HTML5, CSS, JavaScript.
- Node is, and NoSQL databases, including RESTful APIs.
- Familiarity with frameworks like React.js and Next.js.
- Proficient in utilizing relevant tools for web development, including GitHub, Postman, and Visual Studio Code.
- Knowledgeable in agile methodologies, particularly Scrum.

Health care and nursing professional

Interdisciplinary Intensive Care Unit

2018 - Currently | Klinikum rechts der Isar, Munich

- Stress resistance Active role in the resuscitation team with precise decision-making under stress.
- Teamwork Effective interdisciplinary collaboration.
- Communication Successful cooperation and coordination within interdisciplinary toams.
- **Time management** Efficient organization of time for critical tasks and strict adherence to medical protocols.
- Willingness to learn and Training Participation in internal training for the implementation and use of the digital documentation system.

Stroke Unit/IMC Nursing

2015 - 2018 | Klinikum rechts der Isar, Munich

• Specialized care for stroke patients, with a particular focus on assessing and implementing individual nursing measures.

Neurological Nursing - Stroke Unit

2012 - 2015 | Nordwest Hospital, Frankfurt am Main

• Effective collaboration within the multidisciplinary team.

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

CS50 - Introduction to Computer Science

2023 - 2024 | Harvard University, Remote

- Foundation in programming languages such as C, Python, and SQL.
- Practical experience in designing and implementing algorithms, data structures, and software development. Final project- Bookmarkify

Wound Expert ICW

2020 - 2021 | Klinikum rechts der Isar, Munich

 Advanced knowledge in wound therapy and competence in the use of technologies and innovative approaches to optimize the healing process.

Special Nursing Stroke-Unit

2014 - 2015 | University Johannes Gutenberg, Mainz

• Competence in the rapid and effective assessment of stroke patients using specialized protocols.

Bachelor of Science in Nursing

2007 - 2011 | Nursing School Coimbra, Portugal

- Skills in practical care and execution of clinical procedures.
- Interpretation of medical examinations and implementation of treatment plans.
- Effective communication and development of empathy and ethical behavior.